SENIOR TECHNOLOGY AND FINANCE PROFESSIONAL

Seasoned, multidisciplinary, bilingual (English/German) executive with over twenty years proven record of improving and aligning business processes through technological advancements in small, medium, large and global organizations. Passion for technology, finance, and problem solving. Focused, energetic, strong interpersonal skills and business judgment. Recently completed degree in Software Engineering with intent to combine previous work experience with new skills in modern software design and data science.

Languages & Frameworks

- Python, Java, JavaScript, UNIX
- SQL, PostgreSQL, Kafka
- Django, Flask, SpringBoot
- Docker, Git
- Keras
- scikit-learn, statsmodels
- Pandas, Numpy, OpenCV
- Bokeh, Matplotlib, Seaborn
- HTML, CSS, Ninja Templating
- Raspberry Pi

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Machine & Deep Learning

- Linear and Logistic Regression
- Basic Reinforcement Learning
- GAMs and Splines
- Non-Parametric Modeling
- Ensemble Methods
- Natural Language Processing
- Transfer Learning
- PCA and Autoencoders
- Computer Vision (CNN)

Business Processes

- Financial Management
- Mergers & Acquisitions
- ERP(SAP) Integrations
- Cash Flow Forecasting
- Budgeting and Forecasting
- Project Management
- Financial Reporting and Analysis
- Process Design and Automation

EXPERIENCE

Harvard Extension	Student - ALM Graduate in Software Engineering		2017-2020
Primetals Technologies	Director – Finance	Worcester, MA	2013-2017
Siemens Industry	Director - Process Management	Worcester, MA	2010-2013
	Director - Global Projects / M&A	Pittsburgh, PA	2005-2010
Siemens Mobile	Chief Information Officer	Boca Raton, FL	2003-2005
	Director of Regional Management	Munich, Germany	2002-2003
Siemens AG	Corporate Performance Controller	Munich, Germany	1999-2002
Siemens Energy & Automation			
	Finance Project Leader SAP FI/CO	Atlanta, GA	1998-1999
	Senior Financial Analyst	Atlanta, GA	1996-1998
	Financial Management Trainee	Atlanta, GA	1994-1996
Management & Planning Services			
	Accounting Consultant	Atlanta, GA	1992-1994

Successive promotions of increasing responsibility, complexity and scope based on strong performance and diversity of skills. Led numerous successful high-impact M&A projects with teams from complex matrix global organizations. Designed, developed and implemented various tools, platforms and algorithms which improved data quality, interpretability, consistency, accessibility and speed.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Technology & Tools

- Spearheaded digital transformation program automating financial processes and allowing staff to focus on cost savings programs, business process improvements and results analysis
- Implemented SAP FI/CO modules at \$200M organization including customized ABAP program interfaces and reports
- Managed the SAP and IT systems for company of 500 users in 13 locations
- Extensive use of advanced Excel, VBA, MS Access and SQL-based solutions for small, ad-hoc customized reporting and analysis tools as well as process automation
- Rolled out Hyperion financial reporting system to 15+ operational locations

Data Modeling and Analysis

- Developed cash and profit forecasting algorithms with 90%+ accuracy
- Implemented sales-driven 'early warning' management system that provided advanced insights into developing market trends and avoided internal logistical conflicts.
- Developed a manufacturing demand calculation process which forecasted annual production and inventory requirements

Financial & Business

- Led financial organization of \$100M service business unit covering multiple locations and international market scope
- Used newly acquired manufacturing facility to lower internal production costs 40% on specific product lines by exploiting unused capacity
- Increased cash flow by lowering outstanding receivables by 50% and cutting days sales outstanding in half
- Due diligence and integration of 20+ newly acquired companies into the Siemens landscape often leading teams of 100+ individuals in various global locations and teams.
- Implemented global transfer pricing structure that adhered to tax regulations and incentivized global collaboration between manufacturing units

EDUCATION

Harvard University Masters of Liberal Arts in Extension, Software Engineering	2020
Georgia State University Master of Science, Computer Information Systems	1999
Iowa State University B.B.A., Accounting, Minor: German	1992

TRAINING & SPECIAL SKILLS

- Harvard University Certificate in Data Science (2020)
- Graduate of the IMD Global Executive Program
- Siemens Management Qualification Training
- Fluent in English (native) and German
- Private Pilot License Single Engine Aircraft